# Alison Altomari

3823 Sunset Drive Los Angeles, CA 90027 (609) 306-1571 Altomari.Alison@gmail.com www.alaalison.com

Merging my rich experience in marketing with my unparalleled passion for food and agriculture, I excel at working directly with producers and purveyors to build successful brands and connecting the dots between consumers and real food.

# Professional Experience

#### California Olive Oil Council

Marketing Director

Berkeley, CA September 2012 – December 2013

Spearheaded the Council's first media dinners in San Francisco, New York and Baltimore; collaborating with reputable chefs to create menus, educating influential media guests and tastemakers, and generating awareness of the California olive oil industry

Strengthened the extra virgin certification program by implementing new evaluation methods for the taste panel and oversaw the certification of 450+ oils, training as a professional taster

Successfully completed redesign of the council's website and logo; transforming the brand image as well as membership communications

#### Monvinic Restaurant

Stage (Culinary Apprentice)
Barcelona, Spain January – April 2012

Gained an informal education in the Spanish language as well as authentic Catalan cuisine by training under each kitchen station, reporting to the executive chef

Facilitated the weekly produce orders and selection from 82 local food purveyors, visiting local markets and live seafood auctions

#### à la Alison, www.alaalison.com

Owner/Creator Philadelphia, PA Sept. 2010 – Present

à la Alison connects travel storytelling and photography with seasonal, regional recipes as well as produces small-batch preserves and pantry items

Personal recipe published in Food52's Cookbook, Fall 2012

Selected to host a video segment for the 2011 Atlantic City Food & Wine Festival

### Agency 51 Advertising

Account Executive
Philadelphia, PA June 2010 – January 2012

Consistently achieved quarterly goals and campaign success through measured reach of target audience as well as an increase in clients' customer base and sales

Collaborated with clients to develop and execute integrated creative campaigns for consumer and business-to-business marketing initiatives across print, broadcast, electronic, and collateral media

Developed creative briefs, production schedules, invoicing, client budget proposals, and internal agency records

## Education

#### **Drexel University**

Philadelphia, PA

Graduated magna cum laude, June 2010

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Marketing Concentration, Communications Minor

Member of the Drexel Pennoni Honors College

Received the following scholarships and awards for academic excellence: A.J. Drexel, Dean of LeBow, Honors College, Betsy Z. Cohen, and Paul R. Moul Scholarships as well as Dean's Service and Warren Cooper Awards

Member of the Student Advisory Board to the Dean of Drexel's LeBow Business College

# Computer Skills

Experienced photographer; trained in photo editing with Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop Elements

Proficient in Microsoft Office, website management, and HTML editing

## Activities

Freelance writer and photographer

Certified Yoga Alliance Instructor

Model for Mill Mercantile and RTH shop